Danny S. Sprouse

dannyssprouse@gmail.com | 404.368.3434 (c) | 404.257.5531 (h) | Atlanta, Georgia

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/danny-sprouse

GitHub: https://github.com/DannySprouse

Portfolio Website: https://dannysprouse.github.io/Professional-Portfolio/

Career Summary

Over 20 years of experience in project management and development. Currently seeking a full-time web development position. Extensive education and decades work experience in analytics, human psychology and marketing positions to be highly skilled as UX/UI and front-end developer. Enjoys leveraging background in education and human psychology to offer unique perspectives on how endusers interface with websites, from design to deployment. Logical thinker with solid skills to understand human behavior and the importance of creativity and aesthetic. Believes clear communication is critical when creating web applications, whether that's crafting them independently or collaborating with others.

Technical Skills

<u>Proficient</u>: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Media Queries, Responsive Design, Mobile First, APIs, UX, UI, Granim.js, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Dreamweaver, Usability Testing Principles, Analytical Thinking, Research, Project Management, Technical Writing, Microsoft Office Suite.

<u>Intermediate Knowledge</u>: JavaScript, jQuery, Git version control, Git Bash/Command Line, Balsamiq, Github, Firebase, JSON, AJAX, SEO, debugging/testing, additional Adobe Suite tools including Illustrator and Premiere Pro.

<u>Novice/Growing Skills</u>: Node.js, React.js, Moment.js, Express.js, Handlebars, C#/ASP.Net, MongoDB, MySQL, WordPress, Heroku, Laravel, Django, React Native, Lodash, algorithms, data structures.

Applications Built: Solo Projects

<u>Psychic Game</u>: A matching game using random generated letters and scoring (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript): https://dannysprouse.github.io/Psychic-Game/

Crystals Collector: A matching game using random generated numbers and scoring (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery): https://dannysprouse.github.io/Crystals-Collector-Game/
Trivia Game: A timed game divided into four regions of the US that calculates score at end of game (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery): https://dannysprouse.github.io/Trivia-Game/
Train Scheduler: A scheduling app with user input, including add and delete, and time calculations (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Moment.js, Wickedpicker.js, Firebase): https://dannysprouse.github.io/Train-Scheduler/

Applications Built: Team Project

<u>Eat. Drink. Play.</u>: An app designed to generate random meal and drink recipes and a game (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, APIs, AJAX, user input validation, Photoshop: https://dannysprouse.github.io/Eat-Drink-Play/

Experience

Positive Impact, Inc., Atlanta, Georgia

6/2002 – present

Associate Director/Department Director

 Acquired multimillion dollar Federal and State contracts to support departmental and agency services

- Grew department from one staff with annual budget of \$70,000 to a current staff of 16 with an annual budget exceeding \$1 million
- Created a unique brand (MISTER) including logo design, typography and color scheme, marketing strategies and promotional materials such as palm cards, business cards and posters
- Managed a team of four mid-level managers and 11 frontline staff
- Migrated department database from Access to SQL to expand data collection and analysis efforts to better evaluate programmatic effectiveness
- Developed, deployed and managed the MISTER brand website

Freelance Photography, Atlanta, GA

11/2010 - present

Freelance Photographer

- Responsible for photographing, printing images or digitally rendering image deck, and customer service
- Process images, edit and retouch photos as needed and restore images using Adobe Photoshop
- Manage digital image database and maintain images on website
- Recruit new clients for individual photoshoot sessions

Private Practice, Atlanta, GA

6/2002 - 5/2017

Private Practice Psychotherapist, LPC

- Conducted extensive psychosocial assessments and generated a treatment plan for each client prior to therapy
- Created treatment plans that were client-centered, so the plan was always tailored to the client need rather than fitting a client into a preconceived plan
- Charted and documented client progress, including treatment plans and progress notes
- Worked with clients to address their problems and increase their coping skills through anger management, relaxation, impulse control, social skills development and emotional coping
- Assisted clients in identifying how thinking impacted behavior and worked with clients to educate on the interplay of thoughts, feelings and behavior

MedQuist, Inc., Atlanta, Georgia

6/1990 - 5/2002

Senior Medical Technology Specialist

- Performed tasks of interpreting and transcribing dictation from physicians on therapeutic and clinical courses
- Maintained references for medical terminology and procedures
- Identified, interpreted and evaluated discrepancies and inconsistences in medical records
- Worked independently from home office via telework agreement with very little management oversight while maintaining error-free work and high quality assurance scores

Sears, Roebuck & Co., Charlottesville, VA

4/1986 - 5/1990

Customer Service Associate/Assistant Training Manager

- Answered customer telephone calls at major call center to manage customer concerns and complaints
- Responded to questions and complaints and escalated calls appropriately
- Recognized by management as highly effective in communications and customer relations and promoted to assistant training manager
- Trained onboarding employees in customer service skills, in phone management of customer complaints, and processed escalated calls to engage with higher level customer concerns

UVA Health System, Charlottesville, VA

9/1981 - 4/1986

Medical Records Specialist

• Conducted medical transcription services from dictated reports by physicians and nursing staff

- Prepared medical charts for auditing
- Completed admission summaries, discharge summaries, and operative reports for admitted patients
- Retrieved patient medical records for medical visits and released information to persons or agencies according to regulations

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Certificate 2018

Georgia Tech Professional Education Coding Bootcamp – Full Stack Web Development An intensive 24-week coding Bootcamp focused on designing and building web applications. Skills learned included HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, Node.JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, React.JS, WordPress, algorithms and data structures.

Georgia State University

Master of Science 2002

Professional Counseling/Education

Georgia State University

Bachelor of Arts 2000

Psychology Major/Sociology Minor

Georgia Perimeter College

Associate of Arts 1997

Psychology Major/Sociology Minor

Licensure: Licensed Professional Counselor (LPC); Georgia State Licensure #LPC004307